翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
大家好
Hello, everyone.
使用AI工具翻译，如有不准确的地方请在弹幕或评论区指正，谢谢！
！！真的有人看不到这行字！！
在这个视频里将要展示
In this video, finally.
（非静止画面）
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
等等
Oh, wait.
♥本视频在Enderman频道会员有效期内翻译♥
稍等
Hold on.
我其实拼错了
I actually misspelled it.
不是CaptchaBot.cc
It's not CaptchaBot.cc.
是C-A-P-C-H-A-Bot.cc
It's C-A-P-C-H-A-Bot.cc.
它要加载了
It's gonna load.
该网站被报告为不安全
This site has been reported as unsafe.
太棒了
Awesome.
这正是我们要找的
That's what we're looking for.
继续访问不安全的网站
Continue to the unsafe site.
嘿 别这样啊
Hey, come on, man.
让我访问验证码
Give me the access to the Captcha.
我四小时前收到这个
I've been sent this four hours ago,
看起来它已经失效了
and it seems like it's already dead,
可能吧
maybe.
或者它在检测我用的代理
Or maybe it's detecting the proxy that I'm using.
哦 等等
Oh, wait.
DNS坏了吗？
Did the DNS break?
不 DNS没坏
No, DNS didn't break.
它在工作
It's working.
*似了喵*
看来恶意网站现在又上线了
So it appears the malicious site is back up now.
我们要访问的是C-A-P-C-H-A-Bot.cc
So we're gonna visit it at C-A-P-C-H-A-Bot.cc.
CaptchaBot 但验证码拼错了
CaptchaBot, but the Captcha is misspelled.
谁在乎呢？
Who cares, anyway?
好了 网站被报告为不安全
Alright, the site has been reported as unsafe.
我们已经看到了
We've already seen that.
这网站有点问题
It has some issues.
老兄 我还得为这个假Cloudflare验证码干活
Man, I gotta work for this fake Cloudflare Captcha.
拜托 兄弟
Come on, brother.
它刚才还能加载
It just loaded.
就在我开始录屏前
Like, before I started recording,
我随手试了个curl请求
I was doing a Hail Mary curl request,
居然成功了
and it actually loaded.
现在又不行了
And it no longer loads.
搞什么鬼？
What the hell?
好了 我要换IP了
Alright, I'm changing the IP.
OK 我又切了一次IP
Alright, I switched the IP one more time.
再试一次
Let's give this a whirl.
哦 太棒了
Oh, awesome.
终于出来了
There we go, finally.
“完成下方操作以验证您是人类”
Verify you're a human by completing the action below.
这里嵌了个iframe
And here we got an iframe.
这个iframe...我的天
And the iframe is... oh my lord.
能直接看源码吗？
Can I just view the source?
这个iframe被判定为不安全
The iframe is considered unsafe,
所以不显示
so it doesn't render.
老天 让我看下源码吧
Oh lord, please, just let me view the source.
可能再也加载不出来了
I might not load this ever again.
iframe在哪？
Where's the iframe at?
源码里有个reference.html
So, and the source is a reference.html.
我们可以单独运行这个
We can run this separately.
好 明白了
Okay, yeah.
他们基本就是抄袭了Cloudflare验证码
So I think they basically ripped off the Cloudflare Captcha,
里面嵌了个iframe
and it contained an iframe,
直接拿Cloudflare模板当蓝本了
so they just used the Cloudflare template as a blueprint.
有没有办法能关掉这个？
Is there any way I can somehow turn this off?
烦死了
It's annoying me.
好了 开始操作
Alright, here we go.
Edge设置 隐私
Edge settings, privacy,
SmartScreen
smart screen.
把这破玩意儿关掉
Turn this crap off.
然后刷新网站试试
And let's update the website to get access to it.
*在 X 上关注！
千万要成功啊
Please work.
我得再换个IP
I want to change the IP again.
好了 搞定了
Okay, we're good.
搞定了
We're good.
又拿到个新IP地址
I got another IP address.
这次得谨慎使用
Let's use it wisely.
访问故意拼错的CaptchaBot.cc
By entering CaptchaBot.cc with Captcha being misspelled.
妙啊！
Lovely!
终于没有微软SmartScreen了
Finally, no Microsoft smart screen.
好了 这就是网站的样子
Okay, so this is how the website looks.
CaptchaBot.cc 请完成下方验证以确认你是人类
CaptchaBot.cc, verify you're human by completing the action below.
本质上就是个山寨版Cloudflare验证码
And essentially, you get a complete ripoff of a real Cloudflare Captcha.
看起来毫无违和感
It doesn't look off at all.
有隐私政策按钮
You get the privacy button,
服务条款按钮
you get the terms button,
还有RayID 装得跟真的一样
you get the RayID, and it looks very genuine.
直到你点击复选框
Until you hit the checkbox.
“正在等待Cloudflare验证您的连接”
Please wait while Cloudflare validates your connection.
“需要额外验证”
Extra verification needed.
“按Win+R打开运行对话框”
Press Windows plus R to open the run dialog,
“按Ctrl+V粘贴验证文本”
paste the verification text by pressing CTRL plus V,
“点击OK确认你不是机器人”
press OK to verify you're not a robot.
这就是为什么 折腾这么久
This is why, all this time,
我在找假的Cloudflare验证码
I was looking for a fake Cloudflare Captcha.
因为它看起来最逼真
Because it looks the most genuine.
我觉得这里应该有一张图片
And I think there's supposed to be an image,
但不知为何图片没有加载出来
but it didn't load for some reason.
等等 不对 它没加载出来
Oh wait, no, it didn't load.
好吧 没有图片
Okay, there's no image.
不过看起来还是挺像真的
Well, it still looks pretty genuine,
对吧？
right?
作为一个技术宅
I mean, as a tech guy,
我明白这是恶意软件 他们想感染我的电脑
I understand this is a malware and they're trying to infect me.
但对于不懂技术的人来说
But as a tech illiterate person,
我可能就直接粘贴了
I might as well just paste that.
这手法相当狡猾
So it's very crafty.
他们利用了运行框的特性
They're using the property of a run box.
这个文本框长度有限 必须向左滚动才能看到真正的命令内容
The fact this text box has a limited length and you have to scroll to the left to get to the actual meat of the command.
而rem在批处理中就是注释
And rem is pretty much a comment in batch.
所以他们只是写了段注释
So they just made a comment,
除了让你忽略实际运行的命令外毫无作用
which does nothing, except abstract you away from the command that they're actually running,
真正的命令藏在最开头
which is at the beginning.
执行的是conhost.exe
And the command is conhost.exe,
启动无头模式 运行cmd脚本
start headless, cmd run script,
进入用户配置文件  然后从这个IP和端口保存a.exe
enter user profile, then save a.exe from this IP and port right here.
然后再次以无头模式运行conhost.exe
And then run conhost.exe headless again,
然后基本上就是运行a.exe
and then pretty much run the a.exe.
就这样
That's it.
这不是MSHTA的方式
It's not the MSHTA way,
但这又是另一种欺骗反恶意软件的手段
but it's another way of tricking the anti-malware into thinking you're actually running conhos,
而conhost正在运行的代码就在这里
and conhost is running this code right here.
让我们看看这到底是怎么回事
So let's see what it's all about.
我完全可以剥离这个命令里的任何部分
I mean, I can pretty much strip anything from this command,
但我打算单独下载这个
but I think I'm gonna download this separately.
漂亮 完美
Yeah, beautiful.
我们成功下载了
We get the download.
它有3MB大小
It's three megabytes long.
很明显 这是个病毒
It's a virus, quite obviously.
它不让我下载
It doesn't let me download,
我想下载它
I want to download it.
我得先把Microsoft Defender关掉
I need to turn off Microsoft Defender first.
Microsoft Defender对恶意程序太敏感了
It's so annoying when it comes to malware.
只要它在 我就没法处理任何恶意程序
I can't do anything with malware whenever Microsoft Defender is around.
不过它本来就应该这样
I mean, that's how it's supposed to be,
对吧？
right?
来看看这个文件的属性
Let's check out the properties of this file.
空的
Nothing.
什么都没有
Nothing here.
真有意思
Very interesting.
那我们就运行这个吧
So that's what we're going to run.
它会保存到我的用户配置文件里
It's gonna save it to my user profile.
就存在这个文件夹
It's gonna save it right here,
然后运行它
in this folder, and then run it.
我打开任务管理器 让你看清发生了什么
I'm gonna run the Task Manager and show you exactly what happens.
点击确定
Press OK.
Conhost正在运行
Conhost is running.
检测到威胁
Threats found.
没关系
Doesn't matter.
出现a.exe
There's a.exe.
这能检测到lobin吗
Is this gonna detect the lobin?
不 它检测到的是...
No, it detects the...
恶意文件本身
malicious file itself,
正在运行的恶意文件
which is running.
之后天知道会发生什么
And then, God knows what happens.
我猜这个可执行文件内置了反虚拟机机制
So I'm assuming this executable has an anti-VM inside of it.
含有反虚拟机代码
It has anti-VM code.
具备虚拟机检测功能
It has VM detection.
所以它不会真正运行...
So it's not going to run...
不会执行任何操作
It's not going to do anything.
任何实质性操作
Anything of importance.
好的 这就是我从虚拟机里提取的a.exe文件
Okay, here's the a.exe I extracted from that VM.
现在我们处于加固的虚拟机环境中
Now we're in a hardened VM.
那我们来看看它会有什么行为
So let's go ahead and see what it does.
我照例运行安装追踪器和进程黑客工具
I'm gonna run the Installation Tracker and Process Hacker as usual.
我就不深入分析这个恶意软件了
I'm not gonna go super in-depth into the malware analysis.
你可以用any.run这类工具来实现
You can do that with tools like any.run.
但我只是想
But I just, you know,
我懒得折腾了 老兄
I can't be bothered, man.
因为这些都是很常见的套路
Because all this is pretty generic.
那就直接运行它吧
But let's go ahead and run that.
正在安装a.exe
Installing a.exe.
出现了
There it is.
应用程序启动
App launch.
applaunch.exe
等等
Hold up.
它似乎在伪装成微软.NET框架
I think it impersonates microsoft.net framework.
哦 它被添加到了启动项
Oh, so it's at a startup value.
这样每次开机都会自动运行
So it's gonna run on every startup.
然后它启动了applaunch程序
And then it started the app launch.
但我实在不太明白为什么
But I don't really quite get why.
有命令行参数吗
Is there any command line?
嗯 其实没有
Well, not really.
applaunch.exe 是干什么用的
What is applaunch for,
我觉得这是个误导线索
I think that's a red herring.
我不认为它有什么实际功能
I don't think it does anything.
它只是把自己保存到一个文件夹里  然后把自己添加到启动项
It just saves itself into a folder and then puts itself on startup.
会不会是窃密程序？
Could it be a stealer?
好的
Okay.
所以它又会再次自启动
So it's gonna start itself yet again.
我有点想看看现在到底什么情况了
I kind of want to see what's going on already.
我需要用Process Hacker来查看
I need Process Hacker for that.
a.exe 刚刚随资源管理器启动了
a.exe just started with Explorer,
显然如此
obviously.
来看看它要做什么
Let's see what it does.
applaunch.exe 老实说
applaunch.exe Honestly,
我完全搞不清楚状况
I don't really know what's going on.
它会不会在往那个进程里注入东西？
Could it be injecting something into that process?
我有点懵
I'm puzzled.
如果评论区有哪位大神想解释这种现象
If anyone in the comments down below want to explain why that happens,
以及它创建applaunch.exe的潜在原因
and what could be the potential reason why it creates applaunch,
欢迎畅所欲言
be my guest.
请在下方留言
Comment down below.
与此同时 我的订阅用户又发来个虚假Cloudflare验证码
And in the meantime, my subscriber sent me another fake Cloudflare captcha,
这域名...我连念都懒得念
which is... I mean, I'm not even gonna read that domain name.
界面长这样
So here's how it looks.
有点不同
It's a little different.
它压根不支持暗黑模式
It doesn't do dark mode at all.
连装都不装一下
It doesn't even try.
但你看 这里根本没有链接
But yeah, you see, there is no link here,
不像CaptchaBot那样
as opposed to CaptchaBot,
这破玩意儿根本加载不出来
which doesn't freaking load,
但我会剪辑进去做个对比
but I'm gonna edit that in to compare.
而且看起来就很假
And it looks kind of fake.
稍微山寨点
It's a little cheaper.
做工明显更廉价
It's a little more cheaply made.
它每次都会重新加载
It reloads every single time.
我什么都做不了
I can't even do anything.
但一旦我们点击“我不是机器人”
But once we click, I'm not a robot.
来看看会发生什么
Let's see what happens.
这就是它的操作
That's what it does.
为了更好地证明你不是机器人...
To better prove you're not a robot...
为了更好地证明你不是机器人
To better prove you're not a robot,
行吧 请便
sure, please.
按住Windows键加R键
Press and hold the Windows key plus R.
在验证窗口中
In the verification window,
按Ctrl V 再按键盘回车键完成
press Ctrl V, press Enter on your keyboard to finish.
你将看到并同意
You will observe and agree.
天啊 老兄
Oh my god, dude.
快点
Come on.
快点 现在
Come on now.
别每次都重启
Stop restarting every time.
你将看到并同意
You will observe and agree.
我不是机器人
I am not a robot.
验证码ID 645221
Recaptcha verification ID 645221.
按照上述步骤完成验证
Perform the steps above to finish verification.
我不明白验证码跟这些有什么关系
I don't know what Recaptcha has to do with any of that,
但好吧
but sure.
我根本没时间点击验证按钮
I didn't have enough time to press verify,
因为每次都会刷新
because it updates every single time.
等等
Oh, wait.
稍等
Hold up.
它有没有复制东西到剪贴板？
Did it copy anything into my clipboard?
让我粘贴到记事本里
Let me unload it into Notepad.
如果Windows的网页搜索能用的话...
If the web search in Windows works...
等等
Oh, wait.
真的
Really.
成功了
It worked.
来看看这家伙到底在干嘛
So let's see what this guy does.
PowerShell
PowerShell.
搜索PowerShell
Search PowerShell.
然后它混淆了字符串
Then it obfuscates the string.
HTTP加S加那部分
HTTP plus S plus that.
它拼接了字符串
It concatenates the string.
没错 这就是绕过反恶意软件检测恶意链接的方法之一
But yeah, that's one of the ways to trick anti-malware into not detecting the malicious links.
通过混淆和拼接字符串
It's to obfuscate and concatenate the strings.
这是其中一种手段
That's one of the ways.
然后它添加了链接
And it just adds the link.
这里又有一段混淆代码
And then another bit of obfuscation here.
它创建了一个对象
It creates an object.
对 我猜就是下载可执行文件然后运行
Yeah, I think it just downloads an executable and then runs it.
至少原理是这样
Well, that's the idea anyway.
我有点不敢运行
I am afraid to run it,
但还是试试吧
but let's do it.
天啊 这看起来太可怕了
Oh God, this looks horrendous,
不过还是通过运行窗口执行吧
but let's do it via the run box.
确定
Sure.
我要...我要规范化操作
I'm gonna... I'm gonna make it canonical.
看看会发生什么
See what it does.
事实证明现在网上充斥着这类虚假的程序
Apparently, I've been proven right now that there's an abundance of these fake captures.
只是我不知道怎么找到它们
I just don't know how to find them.
真的什么都没发生？
It really does nothing?
什么？
What?
不可能
No way.
肯定...
It must be...
为什么它会自动关闭？
Why does it self-close?
启动PowerShell
Let's start PowerShell.
天啊 别这样
Oh my god, come on.
哦 它在下载一个txt文件
Oh, it's downloading a txt file.
是啊 当然
Yeah, sure.
当然
Sure.
然后大概会把t替换成e之类的
And then it's probably like replacing t's with e's.
某种类似的替换操作
Some kind of thing like that.
$c是个变量
$c, that's a variable.
我们...来还原混淆字符串
Well, let's... let's restore the obfuscated string.
这还挺有意思
That's kind of fun.
等等 什么？
Wait, what?
哦 刚才卡了一下
Oh, it just lagged for a bit.
我们快速反混淆一下
Let's deobfuscate that real quick.
阿里巴巴巴巴
Alibabababa.
等等 阿拉巴巴
Wait, alabababa.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
kh在哪？
Where's kh?
哦 kh等于那个加b
Oh, wait, kh is that plus b,
也就是双斜杠加$c
which is the double slash plus $c,
也就是cvg加后面那些
which is cvg plus all that.
i是什么？
What is i?
i已经是...可执行脚本的一部分
i is already... it's a part of the executable script.
哦 没了
Oh, it's gone.
是吗？
Is it?
阿拉巴巴巴巴
Alababababa.
所以才会失败
This is why it's failing.
好吧
Okay, yeah.
这些虚假验证页面正是通过这类花招来绕过反病毒检测
But yes, this is another tricky kind of thing that these fake captures employ to avoid anti-malware detection.
这是个假冒的Cloudflare验证
Yeah, and that's a fake Cloudflare capture.
这个假得太明显了
This one is not plausible at all.
不过之前那个验证机器人页面做得还挺像样的
The capture bot one was pretty good, though.
这点得承认
I'm gonna give them that.
放进运行框里
Put that in the run box.
发现是相同IP相同端口相同文件
Find out it's the same IP and the same port and the same file.
原标题：Can you spot this Fake CAPTCHA  原作者：Enderman
原视频上传日期：2025年8月7日
这下可以结案了
And we can be done with that.
感谢观看 保重
Thanks for watching and take care.
在 Youtube 上关注
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
♥本视频在Enderman频道会员有效期内翻译♥
如果你喜欢这个视频，请多多支持和评论哒~ o((>ω< ))o
字幕制作不易，喜欢的话支持一下我吧！